<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Jherek Healy</title>
    <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Jherek Healy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:50:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fifth Edition E-Book</title>
      <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/fifth_edition_ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/fifth_edition_ebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fifth edition of the book is now available in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;e-book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; PDF format on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lulu.com/shop/jherek-healy/applied-quantitative-finance-for-equity-derivatives/ebook/product-7kvzmpd.html&#34;&gt;Lulu&lt;/a&gt;. It is soon going to be availabel in&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;color&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hardcover or paperback on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This color edition brings the following minor updates:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vanilla option pricing under the spot piecewise-lognormal model has been reworked and now include newer approximations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asian option pricing also includes newer approximations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Time-dependent piecewise-constant stochastic volatility vanilla pricing, calibration and simulation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A small section on forward variance model calibration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example code for a set of important algorithms detailed in this book are available on the github Julia code repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jherekhealy/AQFED.jl&#34;&gt;AQFED.jl&lt;/a&gt;. The code is experimental, not production grade and subject to changes. More will appear progressively, along with a more precise documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Edition in Colors</title>
      <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/fourth_edition_in_colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/fourth_edition_in_colors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth edition of the book is now available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;DE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;FR&lt;/a&gt;) as hardcover, printed in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;colors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some chapters have been split and their order has been updated. In terms of content, vanilla option pricing under the spot piecewise-lognormal model has been reworked and now includes newer approximations. The pricing of American options under negative rates adds the latest developments of Andersen and Lake. The sections on the finite difference method have been significantly updated, especially around grid stretching, payoff smoothing, the solution of the linear complementary problem under negative rates, and explicit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;super-time-stepping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; schemes. A variety of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;arbitrage-free&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; representations for implied volatilities has been added, as well as an in-depth comparison of the various techniques on a set of concrete market data. Finally the chapter on stochastic volatility now includes simulation and calibration of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;rough volatility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; models.&#xA;More minor changes include the addition of the SABR approximation for basket option prices along with new details on the Black-Scholes approximations, a more careful summation for Monte-Carlo, the Jacobian based Vega for stochastic volatility models, fixing typos around the pricing of variance swaps, which also now presents more challenging examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Edition and Code Repository</title>
      <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/third_edition_and_code_repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 15:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/third_edition_and_code_repository/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A third edition of the book is now available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Applied-Quantitative-Finance-Equity-Derivatives/dp/B08VCM9HBL/&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Applied-Quantitative-Finance-Equity-Derivatives/dp/B08VCM9HBL/&#34;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/Applied-Quantitative-Finance-Equity-Derivatives/dp/B08VCM9HBL/&#34;&gt;DE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/Applied-Quantitative-Finance-Equity-Derivatives/dp/B08VCM9HBL/&#34;&gt;FR&lt;/a&gt;) as paperback and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lulu.com/en/us/shop/jherek-healy/applied-quantitative-finance-for-equity-derivatives-third-edition/hardcover/product-n688ye.html&#34;&gt;Lulu&lt;/a&gt; as hardcover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this third edition, the physical exercise feature is briefly discussed in the first two chapters. The section on how to imply the Black-Scholes volatility has been updated, with the improvements discussed &lt;a href=&#34;https://quantsrus.github.io/post/implied_volatility_algorithms_go_julia/&#34;&gt;in my blog&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;More details around the projected successive over-relaxation method for the pricing of American options have been added, as well as the relatively recent policy iteration method, particularly relevant in the case of negative interest rates, in Chapter 3. A more significant update is the presentation of the Andersen-Lake algorithm instead of the Ju-Zhong formula as fast pricing routine for the case of vanilla American options under the Black-Scholes model with constant parameters.&#xA;Chapter 4 has been updated around random number generation, antithetic variates, and the vectorization of the Monte-Carlo simulation.&#xA;Important corrections have been made around the pricing of forward starting options with finite difference methods in Chapter 8, as well as to the pricing of knock-in options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-publishing, Amazon KDP vs Lulu.com</title>
      <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/self_publication_amazon_kdp_vs_lulu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 15:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/self_publication_amazon_kdp_vs_lulu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initially, I published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lulu.com/shop/jherek-healy/applied-quantitative-finance-for-equity-derivatives-second-edition/hardcover/product-n688ye.html&#34;&gt;my book&lt;/a&gt; through the simplest solution, Amazon CreateSpace, now known as Amazon KDP. The experience was overall great. Amazon KDP allows to print the book in the size of our choice. The standard paper quality is good and the cover looks very much like the digitally uploaded picture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people prefer a &lt;em&gt;hardcover&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;paperback&lt;/em&gt; for durability. Unfortunately, a &lt;em&gt;hardcover&lt;/em&gt; publication is not possible with Amazon KDP. After searching on the web and reading various articles about other sites, which permit self-publication of hardcover books, I decided to try Lulu.com, even if I was a bit scared by &lt;a href=&#34;https://artplusmarketing.com/scam-alert-stay-away-from-lulu-how-to-self-publish-a-book-part-5-adfb05580951&#34;&gt;this very negative review&lt;/a&gt;. The other options I looked at were either not appropriate for a math book, more complex to setup, or more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About the cover: implied volatility fractals!</title>
      <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/about_the_cover_implied_volatility_fractals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 15:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/about_the_cover_implied_volatility_fractals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you will have probably already noticed, the front and back pictures of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;my book&lt;/a&gt; are fractals. But they are not just any fractal.&#xA;They are generated by coloring the number of iterations needed to solve the implied volatility of a vanilla option of a given price in the complex plane, using&#xA;a root finding algorithm like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton%27s_method&#34;&gt;Newton&amp;rsquo;s method&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Householder%27s_method&#34;&gt;Householder&amp;rsquo;s method&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Each point corresponds to a complex implied volatility guess and the more iterations needed, the darker is the point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is so special about this book?</title>
      <link>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/applied_quantitative_finance_for_equity_derivatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jherekhealy.github.io/posts/applied_quantitative_finance_for_equity_derivatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site is dedicated to my book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;Applied Quantitative Finance for Equity Derivatives&lt;/a&gt; sold on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;DE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/dp/B0CM9TL63J&#34;&gt;FR&lt;/a&gt;) as hardcover in colors. The book presents the most significant equity derivatives models used these days.&#xA;It is not a book around esoteric or cutting-edge models, but rather a book on relatively simple and standard models, viewed from the angle of a practitioner. A lot of&#xA;books present models in an abstract manner, often disconnected from how to apply&#xA;those in the real world. This book is different and explains all the details needed for an implementation of the models, at the cost of being relatively succint on the mathematical origins of the various models considered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
